MITHAT KARA



Personal

Address
Menemen/Izmir

Nierieriieri/iZiriii

Phone number +905050709336

Email mithatkara93@gmail.com

Date of birth 21-09-1993

Place of birth Odemis/Izmir

Military service Done

Marital status
Single

Driving licence

Website https://github.com/karamithat

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/mithat-kara/

Languages

English



My name is Mithat. I graduated from the department of business administration in 2017. I have experience in various industries. But I realized that I am not happy with the work I do. I started working on software during the pandemic period. I started to feel good. Since that day, I spend my time improving myself and learning. I'm taking a frontend developer course with Angular and React js at Bilge Adam. I want to progress by working in a deeprooted and big company by improving myself. Being a follower of technological and strategic developments in the sector, to grow and progress together with a company.Positions I am interested in Frontend Developer, React Developer, JS Developer

Work experience

Service Delivery Consultant

Jul 2020 - Feb 2021

Mayen, Izmir

I helped to Arçelik customers in solving technical problems in their household appliances. I forwarded the customers complaints to the relevant department

Computer Operator

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

Yurtiçi Kargo, Izmir

I carried out the operational processes of the incoming cargoes.

Education and Qualifications

Business Administration Sep 2012 - Jul 2017

Gazi University, Ankara

Web Design and Coding Sep 2020 - Jun 2022

Anadolu University, Eskisehir

Skills

Html5	
Css3	
Bootstrap 5	
JavaScript	
React	
Angular	$\bullet \bullet \circ \circ \circ$
JQuery	

Courses

Front End Development with AngularJS and ReactJS Bilge Adam

Oct 2021 - Mar 2022

In this training, the differences of server-side and client-side programming, the basics of the JavaScript programming language; Topics such as the use of jQuery, Bootstrap, TypeScript, Angular, ReactJS and Node.js framework are included.

Projects

• Film Project with React

I developed a project where I can learn the basics of React .I designed the design part with Boostrap.I used the axios library to pull the data.I used TMDB site as an API. I did not use any hooks and state management.We can apply crud operations on movies. You can find the source code at this link. (https://github.com/karamithat/my-movies)

Weather App

I developed a simple weather app. I designed the design part with Css3. I just used Vanilla JS. I used openweathermap site as an API.

Books App

I developed with React. I used Context Api as state management. We can provide theme changes on the site. We can apply crud operations on books